Contact

11805 State Highway 205 Lavon, TX 75166 469-338-8249 (Mobile) chrisescandon@hotmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/christy-escandon-58828223 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Hospitals
Healthcare
Nursing

Honors-Awards
DFW Great 100 Nurse 2011

Christy Escandon

CNO at UT Health Tyler

Dallas, Texas

Summary

As a nursing/healthcare executive with more than 20 years' experience in hospital operations and leadership, I am seeking the next challenge in my career. I have successfully led organizations to the highest level of nursing excellence, clinical quality, financial performance and fostered an environment of engagement and innovation. My teams have achieved the highest level of performance in all regulatory surveys. Additionally, I have overseen construction of two multi-million-dollar hospital expansion projects and re-designed operations from the ground up. I am interested in applying my experience and knowledge in both traditional and new business endeavors. I am outcomes-oriented with an affinity for process improvement.

Experience

UT Health East Texas
CNO
January 2020 - Present (7 months)

Texas Health Plano CNO March 2015 - October 2019 (4 years 8 months) Plano, TX

Texas Health Allen CNO July 2013 - March 2015 (1 year 9 months) Allen, TX

Medical City Children's Hospital Vice President, Operations May 2008 - May 2013 (5 years 1 month) Nursing and daily operations of 137-bed comprehensive service children's hospital. Also includes strategic growth and development planning and implementation. Oversight of quality clinical care provided to our patients.

Edinburg Regional Medical Center / Edinburg Children's Hospital Chief Nursing Officer (CNO)
January 2006 - May 2008 (2 years 5 months)

Valley Healthcare Alliance CNO/COO 2005 - 2007 (2 years)

Education

Western Governors University

Master of Science - MS, Nursing Administration · (2016)

West Texas A&M University MBA, Business · (1999 - 2002)

West Texas A&M University BSN, Nursing · (1997 - 1999)